DANIEL **PESSOA**

Cobalto.dev
daniel@cobalto.dev

linkedin.com/in/cobalto iii



PROFILE

Graduated in Computer Science from Veiga de Almeida University with a solid background in desktop and web applications development using the Microsoft technology stack (WPF, WCF, ASP.NET Core, EF Core and Web API), relational and Non-relation databases (Sql Server, Oracle, MySql & MongoDB) and Cloud Services (Azure). Additionally, experienced with bot development projects and other Machine Learning services with IBM Watson.



EDUCATION & CREDENTIALS

Bachelor of Computer Science | Veiga de Almeida University (UVA) | 2011 MCSD App Builder Training Course | Infnet Institute | 2018

CERTIFICATIONS

Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 (70-480) | Microsoft Developing Microsoft Azure and Web Services (70-487) | Microsoft IBM Certified Application Developer - Watson V3 Certification | IBM Big Data – Extension Course | Veiga de Almeida University (UVA) & MIT

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

.Net Developer | Warren Brasil

10/2020 - PRESENT

Analysis, Development and Maintenance with .Net

Development of new features and maintenance of "Global Portfolio" squad's microservices which actuates as entry point for the user on the platform and includes data from the structural verticals and the integration between those microservices.

.NET Core; MySQL; Web API; Microservices; Kafka; Windows Services; JIRA;

.Net Developer | Sindus ANDRITZ

06/2019 - 09/2020

Analysis, Development and Maintenance with .Net and Python

- Development of new features and maintenance of the Industrial Automation Platform Metris working on its front end with WPF (PIMS Team) and data acquisition from industrial sensors networks (CONNECTORS Team).

Technical Skills: ASP.NET; WPF; Web API; .NET Core; OpenAPI; SQL Server; Python

.Net Developer / Analyst | SONDA TI

09/2018 - 05/2019

Client: Transpetro

Projects: CAST; GETIC Web; FLOW; PLAI;

Analysis, Development and Maintenance with .Net

- Leading role on the conception, modeling and implementation of the company's new transparency portal (PLAI) using ASP.Net Core Web API and MongoDB.
- Development of new features and maintenance of TRANSPETRO's access control system (CAST) and storage and transmission control system of oil products (FLOW) with .Net MVC 5. Technical Skills: ASP.NET; MVC; Jquery; Web API; Dapper; MongoDB; ASP.NET Core; Swagger;

Bots Consultant | CADS Consultoria de Sistemas

05/2017 - 09/2018

Consultant and training service of Chatbots for custom projects.

- Development of custom interfaces for interaction with bot services.

Technical Skills: IBM Watson; ASP.NET Core; Azure;

BI Consultant in Qlikview | CADS Consultoria de Sistemas

01/2016 - 09/2018

- Consulting, development and design for Business Discovery and Business Intelligence.

Technical Skills: QlikView; QlikSense;

.Net Developer / Analyst | CADS Consultoria de Sistemas

11/2013 - 09/2018

Project: SGSC - Credit Insurance Management System

- Development and maintenance of the Credit Insurance Management System

Project: Plancads and auxiliary dashboards

- Analysis and development of budget monitoring management solutions, operational and administrative costs, financial indicators and budget execution using data mining OLAP tools on Oracle database.

Technical Skills: ASP.NET; Javascript; ActiveX; WPF; WCF; Silverlight; ETL; OLAP; MOLAP; TFS;

.Net Developer | Stone Pagamentos

06/2013 - 11/2013

- Analysis and development of technological solutions for the capture, transmission, processing and financial settlement of transactions carried out by plastic cards or by digital means (e-commerce).

Technical Skills: ASP.NET; MVC; REST; WCF; TFS; FTP; Windows Services;

.Net Developer | CADS Consultoria de Sistemas

04/2011 - 03/2013

Client: Petrobras

Project: Plancads and auxiliary dashboards

- Analysis and development of budget monitoring management solutions, operational and administrative costs, financial indicators and budget execution using data mining OLAP tools on Oracle database.

ASP.NET; Javascript; ActiveX; WPF; WCF; Silverlight;



ACHIEVEMENTS

Prêmio Destaque TIC 2012 | Petrobras (Petróleo Brasileiro S.A.)

First place on the in-company highlight award for the year of 2012 with the project "GERA - Gestão de Resultados" (Results Management) for the Supply Division of the Company.